<chapter id="sum.installation">
    <title>Software Installation</title>

    <sect1 id="sum.installation.plugin">
        <title>The MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy toolbox as BEAM plugin</title>
        <para>
            As a BEAM plugin, the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy toolbox needs the following software to be installed
            in advance:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    BEAM, version 4.7.1
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            The BEAM software can be obtained from the BEAM download page
            (www.brockmann-consult.de/beam). Note that the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox software has been
            developed in the frame of BEAM 4.7 and is not compatible with older BEAM versions.
            Once newer releases of BEAM are published, the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox software
            will be updated accordingly if required.
        </para>

        <para>
            The MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox software delivery consists of seven jar files:
            a core module, the module for AATSR recalibration, the modules for
            preprocessing, cloud screening, aerosol and SDR retrieval,
            and adjusted BRR (Bottom of Rayleigh Reflectance) and SDR (Surface Directional
            Reflectance) modules, which provide additional Java classes used by the toolbox:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    beam-meris-aatsr-synergy-core-1.1.1.jar
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    beam-meris-aatsr-synergy-aerosol-retrieval-1.1.1.jar
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    beam-meris-aatsr-synergy-preprocessing-1.1.1.jar
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    beam-meris-aatsr-synergy-cloud-screening-1.1.1.jar
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    beam-aatsr-recalibration-1.1.1.jar
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    beam-meris-brr-2.2.jar
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    beam-meris-sdr-2.2.jar
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>

            <para>
                These files can be installed with the
                BEAM module manager. This is the usual and recommended way. See BEAM help documentation for details
                (http://www. brockmann-consult.de/beam/doc/help/visat/ModuleManager.html).
            </para>
            <para>
                Alternatively, the files can be downloaded from the BEAM plugin page:
                <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                    <listitem>
                        http://www.brockmann-consult.de/cms/web/beam/plug-ins
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
                or the Synergy Wiki page:
                <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                    <listitem>
                        http://www.brockmann-consult.de/beam-wiki/display/SYN/Software
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>

                In this case, the files need to be copied manually into the 'modules' folder of the BEAM
                installation (<xref linkend="figure.installation.beammodules" xrefstyle="select: label"/>).
                Note that existing versions of these jar files need to be replaced/overwritten.
                There should not be more than one jar file for each of these modules in the
                'modules' folder!
            </para>
        </para>

        <figure id="figure.installation.beammodules">
            <title>Installation of MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox jar files in BEAM modules folder (shown for Windows XP)</title>
            <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/beammodules.png"/>
        </figure>

    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.installation.auxdata">
        <title>Auxiliary Data</title>
        <para>
            To be able to process all options properly, the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox processor needs the following
            auxiliary data:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    Ocean aerosol lookup tables (provided by FUB)
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Land aerosol lookup tables (provided by SU)
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Surface reflectance spectra files (provided by SU)
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Lookup tables for Glint algorithm in ocean aerosol retrieval (provided by FUB)
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>

        <sect2 id="sum.installation.auxdata.format">
            <title>Data Format</title>
            <para>
                The aerosol lookup tables come as separate files for each wavelength and each aerosol model.
                Overall, there are 40 aerosol models available for both land and ocean aerosol retrieval.
                </para>
                    <para>
                For the land aerosol retrieval, there are LUTs for the 13 MERIS wavelengths 412, 442, 490,
                510, 560, 620, 665, 681, 708, 753, 778, 865 and 885 nm, and the 4 AATSR wavelengths
                550, 665, 865 and 1610 nm. Therefore, the full set of land aerosol LUTs comprises
                680 files. Although these files are in binary format, the total size is more than 6 GB.
                For more details on the file contents, see [3] and [6].
            </para>
            <para>
                For the ocean aerosol retrieval, there are LUTs for the 4 AATSR wavelengths
                778, 865, 885 and 1610 nm. Therefore, the full set of ocean aerosol LUTs comprises
                680 files. These files are provided in NetCDF format, the total size is about 380 MB.
                For more details on the file contents, see [2] and [6].
            </para>
            <para>
                The default surface reflectance spectra are provided in two small ASCII files.
                The user can specify own reflectance spectra files as processing parameter.
                For more details on the file contents, see [3] and [6].
            </para>
            <para>
                The lookup tables for Glint algorithm in ocean aerosol retrieval are provided as
                two small netCDF files. For more details on the contents of these files, see [2] and [6].
            </para>

        </sect2>
        <sect2 id="sum.installation.auxdata.download">
            <title>Download and Installation</title>
            <para>
                Since the full auxiliary dataset is rather large due to the LUTs for land aerosol retrieval,
                the auxiliary data are provided as a 'standard' and a 'full' bundle. The standard bundle
                only contains the three land aerosol models required for the retrieval in default mode
                (see <xref linkend="sum.toolbox.aerosol" xrefstyle="select: label"/>),
                which reduces the size of the zip archive to below 1 GB. This is sufficient for most use cases.
                To specify an own list of land aerosol models to be used by the algorithm,
                advanced users need to download and install the full bundle.
            </para>
            <para>
                The auxdata can be downloaded from the BC ftp site:
                <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                    <listitem>
                        ftp.brockmann-consult.de
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        username: synergy
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        password: MER_ATS_SYN
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        cd to meris-aatsr-synergy/auxdata
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        download either 'beam-meris-aatsr-synergy-auxdata-standard.zip' or
                        'beam-meris-aatsr-synergy-auxdata-full.zip'
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        extract the archive into your $(user.home)/.beam folder
                    </listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </para>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.installation.addons">
        <title>Additional Requirements</title>
        <para>
            To be able to process all options properly, the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox processor needs the following
            add-ons to be installed in BEAM (if not already done):
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    MERIS L2 Auxdata module
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            The MERIS L2 Auxdata can be installed with the
            BEAM module manager. This is the usual and recommended way. See BEAM help documentation for details
            (http://www. brockmann-consult.de/beam/doc/help/visat/ModuleManager.html).
            In case of failure, you can alternatively download and install from the BC ftp site as described above:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    again, cd to meris-aatsr-synergy/auxdata
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    download 'beam-meris-l2auxdata.zip' and 'beam-meris-l2auxdata-1.1.jar'
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    extract the archive 'beam-meris-l2auxdata.zip' into your $(user.home)/.beam folder
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    copy the file 'beam-meris-l2auxdata-1.1.jar' into the 'modules' folder
                    of your BEAM installation
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <para>
            IMPORTANT:
            Note that it is MANDATORY to install the MERIS L2 Auxdata module, otherwise the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox
            (and possibly many other tools) will not appear in the BEAM Visat 'Tools' menu!
            </para>
    </sect1>

</chapter>
