<chapter id="sum.installation">
    <title>Software Installation</title>

    <sect1 id="sum.installation.plugin">
        <title>Aerosol and SDR Retrieval as BEAM plugin</title>
        <para>
            As a BEAM plugin, the Aerosol and SDR Retrieval processor needs the following software to be installed
            in advance:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    BEAM, version 4.7
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            The BEAM software can be obtained from the BEAM download page
            (www.brockmann-consult.de/beam). Note that the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox software has been
            developed in the frame of BEAM 4.7 and is not compatible with older BEAM versions.
        </para>

        <para>
            The MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox software delivery consists of four jar files, the modules for
            aerosol and SDR retrieval, cloud screening
            and adjusted BRR (Bottom of Rayleigh Reflectance) and SDR (Surface Directional
            Reflectance) modules, which provide additional Java classes used by the toolbox:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    synergy-core-1.1.jar
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    synergy-aerosol-retrieval-1.1.jar
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    synergy-preprocessing-1.1.jar
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    synergy-cloud-screening-1.1.jar
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    beam-aatsr-recalibration-1.1.jar
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    beam-meris-brr-2.1-SNAPSHOT.jar
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    beam-meris-sdr-2.3-SNAPSHOT.jar
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            These files need to be copied into the 'modules' folder of the BEAM
            installation (<xref linkend="figure.installation.beammodules" xrefstyle="select: label"/>).
            Note that existing versions of these jar files need to be replaced/overwritten.
            There should not be more than one jar file for each of these modules in the
                'modules' folder!
            
        </para>

        <figure id="figure.installation.beammodules">
            <title>Installation of MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox jar files in BEAM modules folder (shown for Windows XP)</title>
            <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/beammodules.png"/>
        </figure>

    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.installation.luts">
        <title>Lookup Tables</title>
        <para>
            To be able to process all options properly, the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox processor needs the following
            lookup tables:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    Ocean aerosol LUTs (provided by FUB)
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Land aerosol LUTs (provided by USwansea)
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            Currently, these LUTs are provided by FUB and USwansea on request.
            Automatic access is in preparation. The LUTs can be deployed anywhere on disk, the path needs
            to be specified in the User Interface when running the processor. 
        </para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.installation.addons">
        <title>Additional Requirements</title>
        <para>
            To be able to process all options properly, the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox processor needs the following
            add-ons to be installed in BEAM (if not already done):
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    MERIS L2 Auxdata module
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    GETASSE30 DEM
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    GETASSE30 DEM reader
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
            The MERIS L2 Auxdata and the GETASSE30 DEM reader can be installed with the
            BEAM module manager. See BEAM help documentation for details
            (http://www.brockmann-consult.de/beam/doc/help/visat/ModuleManager.html).
            The GETASSE30 DEM can be downloaded from the BEAM download page. See also
            BEAM help documentation
            (http://www.brockmann-consult.de/beam/ doc/help/visat/GETASSE30ElevationModel.html).
        </para>
    </sect1>

</chapter>
