<chapter id="sum.toolbox">
    <title>Processors</title>

    <para>
        The MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy toolbox can be invoked from the BEAM 'Tools' menu as shown below.
    </para>
    <figure id="figure.visat.synergy">
        <title>The MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy toolbox in BEAM Visat</title>
        <graphic scale="40" fileref="figures/synergy_in_beam.png"/>
    </figure>

    <sect1 id="sum.toolbox.io">
        <title>I/O Parameters and Preprocessing</title>
        <para>
            The Synergy Preprocessor is the first of three main modules within the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy toolbox.
            Its purpose is to create a colocated MERIS/(A)ATSR L1b product containing radiances/reflectances of
            all channels of both MERIS and AATSR. This colocated product shall be used as input for the cloud screening
            module.
        </para>
        <para>
            There is no separate user interface for the Synergy Preprocessor,
            also, there are no processing parameters. The preprocessor is invoked automatically
            when a MERIS/AATSR colocated product is generated either as final product or as intermediate
            product required for cloud screening or aerosol retrieval. These options are provided through
            radio buttons on the Synergy Toolbox I/O Parameters Tab Pane (see below).
        </para>

        <sect2 id="sum.toolbox.io.io">
            <title>I/O Parameters Tab Pane</title>

            <figure id="figure.toolbox.io.iotab">
                <title>Synergy Toolbox: I/O Parameters Tab Pane</title>
                <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/iotab.png"/>
            </figure>

            This tab pane consists of the following components:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    MERIS source product file: Select the source product file by either typing the product path into the
                    text
                    filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                    This source product must be a standard MERIS L1b product.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    AATSR source product file: Select the source product file by either typing the product path into the
                    text
                    filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                    This source product must be a standard AATSR L1b product.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Target product file: Select the target product file by either typing the product path into the text
                    filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Target product format and target directory:
                    <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                        <listitem>
                            'Save as': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will be saved to disk.
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            Target product format: Select one of the available output product formats.
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            Select the target product directory by either typing the product path into the text
                            filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Open in Visat': If this checkbox is selected, the output product is opened in Visat
                    after successful processing.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    Target product specification: This user option is represented by radio buttons
                    and specifies the computation type and results written to the target product:
                    <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                        <listitem>
                            'Only create a colocated MERIS/AATSR product':
                            If this radio button is selected, just a colocated MERIS/AATSR product
                            will be generated. No cloud screening or aerosol retrieval is performed.
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            'Create a cloud screening product':
                            If this radio button is selected, a cloud screening product
                            will be generated. A colocated MERIS/AATSR product is created as intermediate
                            product. No aerosol retrieval is performed.
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                            'Create an aerosol and atmospheric correction product':
                            If this radio button is selected, an aerosol and atmospheric correction product
                            will be generated. Atmospheric correction over land can be added by aerosol
                            retrieval user option
                            (see<xref linkend="sum.toolbox.aerosol" xrefstyle="select: label"/>)
                            The aerosol retrieval processor automatically
                            creates a colocated MERIS/AATSR product and performs cloud screening
                            as foregoing steps.
                        </listitem>
                    </itemizedlist>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </sect2>

        <sect2 id="sum.toolbox.io.control">
            <title>Control Buttons</title>

            From the 'I/O Parameters' tab pane, the following control buttons can be accessed:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    'Run': If this button is clicked, the processor will start the computations.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Close': If this button is clicked, the 'MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox' dialog is closed.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Help': If this button is clicked, this manual is displayed as online help.
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>

            <figure id="figure.toolbox.io.controlbuttons">
                <title>Synergy Toolbox: control buttons</title>
                <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/controlbuttons.png"/>
            </figure>

        </sect2>

    </sect1>


    <sect1 id="sum.toolbox.cloudscreening">
        <title>Cloudscreening</title>
        <para>
            The Cloud Screening Processor is the second of three main modules within the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy toolbox.
            Its purpose is to add various bands (i.e cloud flags) to the colocated MERIS/(A)ATSR L1b product
            obtained from the preprocessor. The output product from the cloud screening shall be used as input for the
            third module (aerosol retrieval and atmospheric correction).
        </para>
        <para>
            The user interface for the Cloud Screening Processor can be accessed by clicking the 'Cloud Screening'
            tab in the 'MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox' dialog.
            (<xref linkend="figure.toolbox.cloudscreening" xrefstyle="select: label"/>):

            <figure id="figure.toolbox.cloudscreening">
                <title>Synergy Toolbox: Cloud Screening Tab Pane</title>
                <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/cloudscreeningtab.png"/>
            </figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            The Cloud Screening tab pane consists of the following components:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    'Use the AATSR forward view when classifying': If his checkbox is selected, the AATSR forward view
                    is considered in the cloud classification algorithm (otherwise nadir view only).
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Compute cloud index': If this checkbox is selected, a cloud index is computed and written
                    as single band 'cloud_index_synergy' to the target product.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Compute snow risk flag': If this checkbox is selected, a snow risk flag is computed
                    and added to a flag band 'cloud_flags_synergy', which is written to the target product.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Compute cloud shadow risk flag': If this checkbox is selected, a cloud shadow risk flag is computed
                    and added to a flag band 'cloud_flags_synergy', which is written to the target product.
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
        <para>
            See [4] for more details on the computation and physical meaning of the quantities listed above.
        </para>

    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.toolbox.aerosol">
        <title>Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction</title>

        <para>
            The Processor for Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction is the third of three main modules
            within the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy toolbox.
            Its purpose is to derive aerosol optical depths over land and/or ocean and (optionally) provide an
            atmospheric correction by using the derived AODs. The processor also makes use of quantities
            derived from the cloud screening module. Therefore, the input for the aerosol retrieval must be
            an output product from the cloud screening.
        </para>

         <para>
            The user interface for the Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction
             can be accessed by clicking the 'Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction'
            tab in the 'MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox' dialog.
            (<xref linkend="figure.toolbox.aerosol" xrefstyle="select: label"/>):

            <figure id="figure.toolbox.aerosol">
                <title>Synergy Toolbox: Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction Tab Pane</title>
                <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/aerosolretrievaltab.png"/>
            </figure>
        </para>

        <para>
            The Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction tab pane consists of the following components:
            <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                <listitem>
                    'Retrieve AODs over ocean': If this checkbox is selected, aerosol optical depths will
                    be retrieved over ocean. The default is 'true'.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Retrieve AODs over land': If this checkbox is selected, aerosol optical depths will
                    be retrieved over land. The default is 'true'.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Retrieve surface directional reflectances (over land only)': If this checkbox is selected,
                    SDRs will be retrieved from rescaled AODs. This computation is performed over land only and
                    requires AOD rescaling (previous checkbox).
                </listitem>
                 <listitem>
                    'N x N average for AOD retrieval': Text field to set
                    the number of pixels to average over in the aerosol retrieval. The default number is '7',
                    which corresponds to a square with 3 pixels to each side of a center pixel.
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                    'Soil surface reflectance spectrum': Text field to set the filename containing
                    the soil surface reflectance spectrum. The default is 'spec_soil.dat',
                    this file is included in the auxiliary data
                    (see <xref linkend="sum.installation.auxdata" xrefstyle="select: label"/>)
                    If the user wants to use a different file, it must be selected via the
                    file chooser button right to the test field. Note that any user selected file
                    must exactly follow the format of the default file.
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    'Vegetation surface reflectance spectrum': Text field to set the filename containing
                    the vegetation surface reflectance spectrum. The default is 'veg_soil.dat',
                    this file is included in the auxiliary data
                    (see<xref linkend="sum.installation.auxdata" xrefstyle="select: label"/>)
                    If the user wants to use a different file, it must be selected via the
                    file chooser button right to the test field. Note that any user selected file
                    must exactly follow the format of the default file.
                </listitem>

                 <listitem>
                     <para>
                         'Use default land aerosol models (recommended)': If this radio button is selected,
                         the default land aerosol models are used for aerosol retrieval. This set of
                         models is included in the 'standard' auxiliary data set
                         (see<xref linkend="sum.installation.auxdata" xrefstyle="select: label"/>).
                         No further user action is required. This option is recommended not only for
                         simplicity, but also because only a small number of models is used.
                         For most purposes, this option will be sufficient.
                         A large number of models (which can be specified with the option below)
                         significantly increases computation time for the aerosol retrieval.
                     </para>
                     <para>
                         For more details on these aerosol models and underlying lookup tables see [3] and [6].
                     </para>
                </listitem>

                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        'Use specific land aerosol models (for advanced users)': If this radio button is selected,
                        specific land aerosol models must be entered by a comma-separated list of model indices
                        in the text field below.
                        To use this option for aerosol retrieval,
                        the 'full' auxiliary data set
                        (see<xref linkend="sum.installation.auxdata" xrefstyle="select: label"/>)
                        must be downloaded and installed.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        For more details on these aerosol models and underlying lookup tables see [3] and [6].
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        'List of land aerosol models': Text field to set a comma separated list of the indices of
                        the aerosol models to be used for the land aerosol retrieval
                        (<xref linkend="figure.toolbox.aerosol.custommodels" xrefstyle="select: label"/>).
                        This text field is enabled only if the 'Use specific land aerosol models (for advanced users)'
                        radio button is selected.
                        The valid range of indices is [1,40].
                        In principle, up to all 40 models could be entered. However,
                        to keep computation time in an acceptable frame, it is recommended to use as few
                        models as possible.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        For more details on these aerosol models and underlying lookup tables see [3] and [6].
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>

        <figure id="figure.toolbox.aerosol.custommodels">
            <title>Synergy Toolbox: Selection of aerosol models for land aerosol retrieval</title>
            <graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/customLandAerosolModels.png"/>
        </figure>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.toolbox.commandline">
        <title>Processing from command line</title>
        Since the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy toolbox makes use of the BEAM graph processing framework, it can be
        used also as a command line tool outside BEAM-VISAT. The graph processing is invoked
        by the command
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        To obtain general help on the graph processing, use the command
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt -h
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        Specific help on the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy toolbox can be obtained with
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt -h synergy.Master
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        In this case, information on the usage and a list of all available parameters are given
        (see <xref linkend="figure.toolbox.gpt" xrefstyle="select: label"/>).


        <figure id="figure.toolbox.gpt">
            <title>'Synergy Toolbox: command line processing</title>
            <graphic scale="40" fileref="figures/synergy_gpt.png"/>
        </figure>

    </sect1>

</chapter>
