<chapter id="sum.processor.aerosolretrieval">
    <title>The Processor for Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction</title>

    <para>
        The user interface for the Processor for Aerosol and SDR Retrieval  is represented by one main dialog, which
        consists of the following components:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 'I/O Parameters' Tab Pane
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Processing Parameters' Tab Pane
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.aerosolretrieval.io">
        <title>I/O Parameters Tab Pane</title>

        <figure id="figure.processor.aerosolretrieval.iotab">
			<title>Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction: I/O Parameters Tab Pane</title>
			<graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/iotab_aerosolretrieval.png"/>
		</figure>

        This tab pane consists of the following components:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                Source product file: Select the source product file by either typing the product path into the text
                filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                The source product must be a colocated MERIS/AATSR product which was generated by the Preprocessor
                module of the MERIS/(A)ATSR Synergy Toolbox AND filled with cloud flags from the Cloud Screening
                module.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                Target product file: Select the target product file by either typing the product path into the text
                filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 Target product format and target directory:
                 <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                    <listitem>
                        'Save as': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will be saved to disk.
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        Target product format: Select one of the available output product formats.
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        Select the target product directory by either typing the product path into the text
                        filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                    </listitem>
                 </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Open in Visat': If this checkbox is selected, the output product is opened in Visat
                after successful processing.
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.aerosolretrieval">
        <title>'Processing Parameters' Tab Pane</title>

        <figure id="figure.processor.aerosolretrieval">
			<title>Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction: 'Processing Parameters' Tab Pane</title>
			<graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/processingtab_aerosolretrieval.png"/>
		</figure>

        This tab pane consists of the following components:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 'Retrieve AODs over ocean': If this checkbox is selected, the aerosol optical depths will
                be retrieved over ocean. The default is 'true'.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Retrieve AODs over land': If this checkbox is selected, the aerosol optical depths will
                be retrieved over land. The default is 'true'.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Path to LUTs for land and ocean aerosol algorithms': Text field to set the path to the
                lookup tables required for the ocean aerosol retrieval. See [2] for more details.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Soil surface reflectance spectrum': Text field to set the filename containing
                the soil surface reflectance spectrum. The default is 'spec_soil.dat' and is included
                in the software package.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Vegetation surface reflectance spectrum': Text field to set the filename containing
                the vegetation surface reflectance spectrum. The default is 'spec_veg.dat' and is included
                in the software package.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'List of land aerosol models': Text field to set a comma separated list of the indices of
                the aerosol models to be used for the land aerosol retrieval. The default is '8,20,28'.
                See [3] for more details.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'N x N average for AOD retrieval': Text field to set
                the number of pixels to average over in the aerosol retrieval. The default number is '7',
                which corresponds to a square with 3 pixels to each side of a center pixel.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Rescale AOD to original resolution after interpolation': If this checkbox is selected,
                the retrieved AODs retrieved on the coarse N x N grid will
                be rescaled to the original resolution by a bicubic interpolation.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Retrieve surface directional reflectances (over land only)': If this checkbox is selected,
                SDRs will be retrieved from rescaled AODs. This computation is performed over land only and
                requires AOD rescaling (previous checkbox).
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.aerosolretrieval.control">
        <title>Control Buttons</title>

        From both tab panes, the following control buttons can be accessed:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 'Run': If this button is clicked, the processor will start the computations.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Close': If this button is clicked, the 'Synergy Aerosol and SDR Retrieval' dialog is closed.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Help': If this button is clicked, this manual is displayed as online help.
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <figure id="figure.processor.aerosolretrieval.controlbuttons">
			<title>Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction: control buttons</title>
			<graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/controlbuttons.png"/>
		</figure>

    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.aerosolretrieval.gpt">
        <title>Processing from command line</title>

        Specific help on the 'Aerosol Retrieval and Atmospheric Correction' processor can be obtained with
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt -h synergy.AerosolRetrieval
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        In this case, information on the usage and a list of all available parameters are given
        (see <xref linkend="figure.processor.aerosolretrieval.gpt" xrefstyle="select: label"/>).


        <figure id="figure.processor.aerosolretrieval.gpt">
			<title>'Synergy Aerosol and SDR Retrieval': command line processing</title>
			<graphic scale="40" fileref="figures/aerosolretrieval_gpt.png"/>
		</figure>

    </sect1>

</chapter>
